A Guide to the L.F. Payne, Jr. Papers, 1988-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
L.F. Payne, Jr. Papers, 1988-1997
The Library of Virginia
39303
30 cubic feet (84 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of L.F. Payne, Jr., Washington, DC.
Biographical Information
Lewis Franklin Payne, Jr. was born in Amherst County, Virginia on 9 July 1945. He graduated from the Virginia Military Institute in 1967. Afterwards, he served in the United States Army and Army Reserve. Payne then earned his M.B.A. at the University of Virginia in 1973. He was a developer of Wintergreen Resort in Nelson County, Virginia, serving as chairman and president of Wintergreen Development, Inc. In 1988, L. F. Payne, Jr. was elected to the United States House of Representatives in a special election to fill the vacancy caused by the death of Wilbur Clarence (Dan) Daniel, and served from 14 June 1988 to 3 January 1997. He was not a candidate for reelection, having resigned to run for lieutenant governor of Virginia. He lost the election to John Hager. Payne now serves as president of McGuireWoods Consulting, LLC in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1988-1997, of L. F. Payne, Jr. (b. 1945) of Nelson County, Virginia, while he represented Virginia's Fifth District in the United States House of Representatives. Payne was also the Democratic nominee for lieutenant governor of Virginia in 1997. Includes legislative files, Democratic Study Group Legislative Reports and House Action Reports, project files, press files, general office files, campaign files, and special media.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Legislative Files.
II. Democratic Study Group Legislative Reports and House Action Reports.
III. Project Files.
IV. Press Files.
V. General Office Files.
VI. Campaign Files.
VII. Special Media.
Contents List
- Series I. Legislative Files, 1988-1996., Extent: 21 boxes. (Box 1-21)
  The legislative files include information on specific legislation or on general topics. There is correspondence from constituents, colleagues, public interest groups, professional organizations, administration officials, and local governments. Also included are internal memos and notes, drafts, final reports and studies, copies of bills, publications, clippings, position papers and talking points, press releases, and copies of testimonies by Payne and others before congressional committees. Some of the topics represented are abortion, balanced budget amendment, banking and insurance, budget reconciliation, Caribbean Basin Initiative, Clinton economic plan, government reform and spending, health insurance reform, Medicare, tobacco legislation, and trade. There is also an overview and information relating to issues affecting the 104th Congress filed at the end of the series. Also included are copies of co-signed letters and co-sponsorship information, legislative activity guides and profiles distributed by the House Clerk, and voting record scorecards and publications from various interest groups.
  Alphabetical
  - A to Z Spending Cuts Bill. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abortion. (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Aggregate Budget Numbers - Entitlements. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Angry Constituent Letters. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Balanced Budget Amendment. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Balanced Budget Amendment, 1992-1994. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Balanced Budget Amendment, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bank Insurance Fund (BIF)/Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF). (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Banking - Insurance. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Banking Legislation - CRS Reports. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Banking Reform. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Budget Reconciliation, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Budget Reconciliation/Trade, 13 September 1995. (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
  - Budget - Republicam Bill (H.R. 2491). (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Burlington Industries (H.R. 1958). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cable Bill. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Caribbean Basin Initiative. (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Clean Air Act. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clean Water Act Reauthorization. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clinton Budget. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clinton Economic Package - Analysis. (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Clinton Economic Plan, 16 July 1993. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Co-Sponsor Letters Signed, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Co-Sponsor Letters Signed, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Co-Sponsor Letters Signed, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - Co-Sponsor Letters Signed, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Comp Time Bill. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Regulations Affecting State, Local, and Tribal Governments, 6 December 1993. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Contract With America" - Text. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - County Economic Profiles. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Credit Card Interest Rate Cap. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Debt Limit Increase. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Deficit Reduction. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Deficit Statement - Ways and Means Markup, 14 March 1995. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - District Hospitals. (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Dole Tax Cuts. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Employee Stock Ownership Plan Bill (ESOP). (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Endangered Species Act. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Estimates of the Earned Income Tax Credit by Congressional Districts, 29 July 1993. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Expedited Rescission Bill, 1993. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Family Tax Credit - Amendments. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Flag Amendment. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Forest Service - Salvage Sales. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gas Tax Repeal. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - GATT - Final Bill. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - GATT - Member Amendments. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - G.O.P. and Drugs. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Government Reform - Talking Points. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Government Reform and Savings Act of 1993 (H.R. 3400). (Box 6, Folder 9-13)
  - Health Insurance Reform. (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Health Insurance Reform. (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Highways. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Immigration. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Insurance. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Labor Analysis. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Legislation Passed - 103rd Congress. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Legislation Passed - 104th Congress. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 100th Congress, Second Session, January-October, 1988. (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 102nd Congress, First Session, January-November, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 7-10)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 103rd Congress, First Session, January-November, 1993. (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 103rd Congress, Second Session, January-November, 1994. (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 104th Congress, First Session, January-December, 1995. (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Legislative Activity Guide, 104th Congress, Second Session, January-October, 1996. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Issues - Staff Memos, 1995. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Legislative Profile, 101st Congress, 9 January 1989 - 2 July 1990. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Profile, 103rd Congress, 5 January 1993 - 9 December 1994. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Profile, 104th Congress, 4 January 1995 - 28 October 1996. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - List of Textile Plants in District. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Medicare - Adjusted Average Per Capita Cost. (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Medicare - Ambulance Services. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Medicare - Antitrust/Malpractice. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Medicare - Articles. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Medicare - Balance Billing/Premium Cap. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Medicare - Clinic Laboratories. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Medicare - Clinical Laboratory Improvement Act. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Medicare - Coalition Health Care Task Force. (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - Medicare - Cochlear Implants. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Medicare - Doctors. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Medicare - Fraud. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Medicare - Graduate Medical Education. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Medicare - HMO's. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Medicare - Home Health and Skilled Nursing Facilities. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Medicare - Home Health Care. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Medicare - Hospice. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Medicare - Hospitals. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Medicare - Indigent Patient. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Medicare - Rep. Nancy Johnson. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Medicare - Medical Savings Accounts. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Medicare - Medicare Dependent Hospitals. (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Medicare - Mental Illness. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Medicare - Oxygen. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Medicare - PT/OT. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Medicare - Pharmacy Project. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Medicare - Point of Service. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Medicare - Preventive Benefits. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Medicare - Rehabilitation Hospitals. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Medicare - Republican Offer. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Medicare - Skilled Nursing Facilities. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Medicare - Subvention. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Medicare - Thomas Proposal. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Minimum Wage. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Motor Voter Legislation. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - NAFTA - Clippings. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - OECD Agreement on Shipbuilding - Hearing, 18 July 1995. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - OECD Shipbuilding Agreement Markup, 13 December 1995. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act, 1990. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Penny/Kasich Budget Proposal. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Public Works and Transportation. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Regulatory Reform/Risk Assessment. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Regulatory Reform/Glass-Steagall. (Box 13, Folder 12-14)
  - Resolution Trust Corporation. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Revenue Estimates - 1996 Budget Bill. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Rules of Origin Hearing, 11 July 1995. (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
  - Savings and Loans. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Securities Amendments of 1996 (H.R. 3005). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Shipbuilding Trade Agreement Act (H.R. 2754). (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Small Business Job Protection Act (H.R. 3448). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Social Security - CRS Reports. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Social Security Notch. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Spending Cuts. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - TEAM Act. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Telecommunications Reform. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Tobacco - Article 28 Authority. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Tobacco - Article 28 Tariff Rate Quote on Tobacco. (Box 15, Folder 4-6)
  - Tobacco - Domestic Use. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Tobacco - General Information. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Tobacco - IRS Compliance Letter. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Tobacco - Interagency Tak Force on Tobacco. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tobacco - Trade Information. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Trade - Bridgeport-Piedmont Tire Case. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Trade - CITA Calls, March, 1995. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Trade - Congressional Textile Caucus/Market Access in GATT. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Trade - Mexico Currency Crisis, 1995. (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
  - Trade - NAFTA Assess - Virginia. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Trade - NAFTA - General Information. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Trade - NAFTA (Good News). (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Trade - OECD Shipbuilding Agreement. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Trade - OECD Shipbuilding Agreement. (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Trade - Paper and Wood Products. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Trade - Pillowtex Corporation, 1995. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Trade - Product Integration, 1995. (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - Trade - Rules of Origin/Regulatory Moratorium. (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
  - Trade - Spratt/Clinton Letters - Customs and NAFTA. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Trade - Temporary Suspension of Duty on Wool (H.R. 1958). (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Trade - Textiles. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Trade - Trade Adjustment Assistance, 1995. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Trade - Trade Adjustment Assistance for Firms - Hearing, 27 May 1993. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Trade - Transshipment Legislation. (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Trade - Transshipments. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Trade - U.S.-Canada Lumber Deal, February 1996. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Unfunded Mandates - Letters. (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - U.S. Troops Under U.N. Control (H.R. 3308). (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Uruguay Round. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Veterans. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Hospital Association. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Voting Ratings and Scorecards. (Box 19)
  - Welfare - Virginia Plan. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Working Families Flexibility Act (H.R. 2391). (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 104th Congress - Activites of Congressional Republicans. (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - 104th Congress - Issues and Overview. (Box 20, Folder 5-11)
  - 104th Congress - Issues and Overview. (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
- Series II. Democratic Study Group Legislative Reports and House Action Reports, 1993-1996., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 22-27)
  The weekly "Legislative Reports" from the Democratic Study Group of the United States House of Representatives, and "House Action Reports" prepared by Congressional Quarterly, were issued from 1993 to 1996. The publications contain information on specific legislation, including the floor situation, background summaries and basic provisions of bills and amendments, arguments for and against, Administration positions, weekly schedules of the House, and fact sheets. Many of the reports pertain to appropriations legislation. Interspersed among the reports are internal office memos to Payne from his staff that also provide background and summaries on specific legislation. This series is arranged alphabetically by agency or subject area.
  - Agriculture/Environment. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Commerce/Justice Appropriations. (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Congressional/Internal Matters. (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
  - Crime/Justice/Law Enforcement. (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
  - Defense Appropriations I. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Defense Appropriations II. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Defense Appropriations III. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Defense/Intelligence. (Box 23, Folder 4-7)
  - Education. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Education/Science Appropriations. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Energy Appropriations. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Federal Budget Appropriations I. (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
  - Federal Budget Appropriations II. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Federal Budget Appropriations III. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Federal Budget Appropriations IV. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - GATT/NAFTA Appropriations. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - General Appropriations. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Health, Welfare, Human Services. (Box 25, Folder 5-8)
  - Intelligence Appropriations. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Intelligence/Foreign Affairs Appropriations. (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Interior/Agriculture Appropriations. (Box 26, Folder 4-7)
  - International Affairs. (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
  - Legislative - General. (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Trade/Commerce. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Transportation Appropriations. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Treasury/Postal Appropriations. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - VA-HUD Appropriations. (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
- Series III. Project Files, 1988-1996., Extent: 11 boxes. (Box 28-38)
  The project files include material on the establishment, construction, renovation, or maintenance of projects of local interest in Virginia's Fifth Congressional district, or issues in which Payne took a specific action. Some of the projects, issues, or groups represented include biotechnology, Buckingham County landfill Superfund site, coal industry retiree health benefits "reachback" provisions, economic development, electric co-ops, Federal Prison Industries, Inc., Interstate 73, the Lake Gaston pipeline project, Medicare reform, power marketing administrations, rural land conservation, the Sandy River Reservoir, and textiles. This series contains notes, clippings, correspondence, interoffice memoranda, background materials, drafts, reports, feasibility studies, grant proposals and notifications, and publications.
  - Air Quality. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Avacado Imports from Mexico. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Bedford D-Day Memorial. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Biotechnology. (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
  - Blue Ridge Region/Economic Development. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Buckingham County Landfill. (Box 28, Folder 7-13)
  - Business Development Conference, Danville, 27 October 1989. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - China - Most Favored Nation Status, 1996. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - China - Textiles and WTO, 1995. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Cigarette Tax/Ukraine. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - The Coalition. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Credit Unions - Tax Exempt Status. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Crouch, Robert P. - U.S. Attorney Nomination. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA). (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Dan Daniel Memorial Park. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - District Meetings, 1995. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Economic Development (Jeffery K. Mitchell). (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Economic Development Administration (EDA) Appropriations FY96 - Letter to Rep. Harold Rogers, 5 June 1995. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Economic Development in Southside, 1990-1991. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Economic Development Meeting Agenda. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Economic Development Plan. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Education - Goals 2000. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Electric Co-ops. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Electric Co-ops/Southeastern Power Administration. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Electric Co-ops/Southeastern Power Administration. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Equity Expansion Act. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - FPI Letter to Attorney General Reno, 15 November 1995. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Federal Prison Industries, Inc., 1989-1991. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Federal Prison Industries (FPI), 1996. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Federal Trade Commission - "Made in U.S.A.". (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Fifth District Economic Development Conference. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Fifth District Economic Development Conference, 4 December 1995. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Generic Speech for L.F., Spring, 1996. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Green Thumb. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Ground Wave Emergency Network (GWEN). (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Highway Projects, 1995. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - I-73. (Box 30, Folder 13-15)
  - I-73. (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - I-73 - National Highway System. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - I-73 - National Highway System, Virginia Map, 1992. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Imperial Coal/Coal Reachback. (Box 31, Folder 5-10)
  - Insurance Negotations, 1995. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Kerr-Philpott Projects - SEPA. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Lake Gaston. (Box 32, Folder 2-12)
  - Lake Gaston. (Box 33, Folder 1-9)
  - Lake Gaston, 1994. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Lake Gaston - Barr, John Y.. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Lake Gaston - Clippings. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Medicare Reform - Rockfish Gap, 24 August 1995. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Manufacturing Center - Martinsville. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Medicare Reform. (Box 34, Folder 4-7)
  - Metric Standard for Rebar. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Moton School. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - National Ground Intelligence Center - Charlottesville. (Box 34, Folder 10-11)
  - National Guard Reduction - 276th Engineer Battalion. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Nellie Mae. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Nottoway Falls Project Meeting, 4 March 1996. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - OTEXA/CITA Funding, 1995. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Overton for U.S. Marshal. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) - Charlottesville Airport. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Patrick Henry Community College Retraining Center, 1992. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Persons with Disabilities Trusts Tax Rate Restoration Act. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Political Matters. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Power Marketing Administrations. (Box 35, Folder 6-11)
  - Reachbax Tax. (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
  - Requested Appointments, 1992-1993. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Richmond/Lynchburg CSO Projects. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Route 50 Corridor Coalition. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Rural Land Conservation Act of 1993. (Box 36, Folder 4-6)
  - Rural Land Revenue Estimates. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Rural Lands. (Box 36, Folder 8-12)
  - Sandy River Reservoir. (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
  - Shenandoah National Park Boundaries. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Short Supply - Trade Legislation. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Superport Gateway 21. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Support Most Favored Nation for China, 1995. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Tariff-Rate Quota (TRQ) on Leaf Tobacco. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - TEAM Act. (Box 37, Folder 10-11)
  - Textile and Apparel Global Competitiveness Act of 1996. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Textile Bill. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Textile Bill/Singapore Hearing. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Textile/Clothing Technology Corporation (TC2) Funding, 1996. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Thanks to Bosnia Troops. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Jefferson Study to Preserve and Assess the Regional Environment (TJSPARE). (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Tire Exports to Mexico. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Trade Adjustment Assistance (TAA) for Firms. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Travel and Tourism. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Uruguay Round Agreements and U.S. Implementing Legislation. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - VMI - Inaugural Parade. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Health Care Foundation. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Primary Care Association, Inc.. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Private Colleges. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Wool Tariff Preference Level (TPL)/Kantor. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - World Trade Negotiations on Financial Services, 1995. (Box 38, Folder 13)
- Series IV. Press Files, 1994-1997., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 39-48)
  The press files include newspaper clippings, photographs and slides, and press releases. The clippings cover the period from January 1994 to September 1996, and include newspaper and magazine articles on state and national politics, as well as stories relating specifically to Congressman Payne, including his statements on various issues, campaign news, and appearances at local events. There are also copies of his weekly column "L.F. Payne...from Washington" and op-ed pieces authored by him that were printed in many newspapers in the Fifth District. There is one folder containing photographs and slides. They include early family photographs, and images of Payne with local citizens, as well as famous dignitaries, including Charles Robb, Al Gore, and Jerry Garcia and Mickey Hart of the Grateful Dead. The press releases date from January 1995 to November 1996. They include drafts and final copies of the release, distribution lists, background information, and staff memorandums. The releases cover Payne's appearances at local events and speeches before constituent groups, his floor statements and congressional testimonies and positions on various issues, legislative actions taken by Congress, grant award announcements, articles and op-ed pieces he wrote, and constituent mailings.
  - Clippings, 1994 (January). (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1994 (February). (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1994 (March). (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1994 (April). (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1994 (May). (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1994 (June). (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1994 (July). (Box 39, Folder 7-8)
  - Clippings, 1994 (August). (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1994 (September). (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings, 1994 (November). (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
  - Clippings, 1994 (December). (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1995 (January). (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1995 (February). (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1995 (March). (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1995 (April). (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1995 (May). (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1995 (June). (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
  - Clippings, 1995 (July). (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
  - Clippings, 1995 (August). (Box 41, Folder 6-7)
  - Clippings, 1995 (September). (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1995 (October). (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1995 (November). (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
  - Clippings, 1995 (December). (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1996 (January). (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1996 (March). (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1996 (April). (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1996 (June). (Box 42, Folder 4)